This video is sponsored by LegalZoom. More about LegalZoom at the end of the video.
이 비디오는 LegalZoom의 후원을 받았습니다. LegalZoom에 대한 자세한 내용은 비디오 끝부분에서 확인하세요.
Hey Wisecrack, Jared again. This is me at the midnight screening of The Dark Knight Rises back in 2012.
안녕 Wisecrack, 다시 제라드야. 2012년에 있었던 '다크 나이트 라이즈' 자정 상영회에서의 나야.
Needless to say, I was out of my mind excited. But despite my Dark Knight infatuation, I couldn't help but be disappointed.
말할 필요도 없이, 나는 미치도록 신이 났다. 하지만 내 다크 나이트에 대한 열정에도 불구하고 실망감을 느끼지 않을 수 없었다.
The Dark Knight Rises is not necessarily a bad movie.
다크 나이트 라이즈는 꼭 나쁜 영화는 아니다.
That comes later.
그건 나중에 올 것입니다.
It just pales in comparison to its predecessor.
그것은 전작에 비해 너무나 색이 바래 보인다.
But as with anything graced with the name Nolan, and by that I mean this one, this film has a lot of intellectual ambition.
하지만 Nolan이라는 이름이 붙은 모든 것처럼, 제가 의미하는 것이 바로 이 영화인 만큼, 이 영화는 많은 지적 야망을 가지고 있습니다.
Unfortunately, not all of it pans out. So let's dive in to see what works and what doesn't.
안타깝게도 모든 것이 잘 풀리는 것은 아닙니다. 그러니 무엇이 효과가 있고 무엇이 효과가 없는지 깊이 들어가 보겠습니다.
Welcome to special Wisecrack Edition on The Dark Knight Rises. What went wrong?
다크 나이트 라이즈에 대한 스페셜 와이즈크랙 에디션에 오신 것을 환영합니다. 무엇이 잘못되었을까요?
And of course, spoilers ahead. A lot of my disappointment with The Dark Knight Rises stems from its smart setup, but
물론, 스포일러가 포함되어 있습니다. "다크 나이트 라이즈"에 대한 저의 많은 실망은 그 똑똑한 설정에서 비롯되지만,
questionable execution.
의심스러운 실행.
So let's start with one of its smartest elements, the very unexpected influence of Charles Dickens' A Tale of Two Cities.
그렇다면 가장 스마트한 요소 중 하나인 찰스 디킨스의 "두 도시 이야기"의 예상치 못한 영향을 시작해 봅시다.
The Dark Knight Rises replicates most of the book's major themes, including social inequality,
다크 나이트 라이즈는 사회적 불평등을 포함하여 책의 주요 주제 대부분을 재현합니다.
resurrection, and doubling. The most obvious thematic parallel with A Tale of Two Cities is social inequality.
부활과 이중성. "두 도시 이야기"와 가장 분명한 주제적 유사점은 사회적 불평등입니다.
The rich don't even go broke the same as the rest of us, huh?
부자들은 우리와 똑같은 방식으로 파산하지도 않네, 그렇지?
The book's setting, the French Revolution, depicts a decadent aristocracy and their abuse of the poor.
책의 배경인 프랑스 혁명은 타락한 귀족들과 그들의 가난한 사람들에 대한 학대를 묘사하고 있습니다.
Likewise, the film portrays a similar class conflict through Bane's false revolution.
마찬가지로, 영화는 베인의 허위 혁명을 통해 유사한 계급 갈등을 묘사하고 있습니다.
Now we come here not as conquerors, but as liberators to return control of this city to the people.
이제 우리는 정복자로서가 아니라, 이 도시의 통제권을 사람들에게 돌려주기 위한 해방자로서 이곳에 옵니다.
The third book in the novel is called Track of a Storm, and Catwoman says,
소설의 세 번째 책은 '폭풍의 흔적'이라고 불리며, 고양이 여인이 말합니다.
There's a storm coming, Mr. Bane.
폭풍이 다가오고 있습니다, 베인 씨.
Then there's the theme of resurrection. In A Tale of Two Cities,
그런 다음 부활의 주제가 있습니다. '두 도시 이야기'에서,
Dickens frequently uses the phrase,
디킨스는 자주 그 표현을 사용합니다.
recalled to life, to signify that his characters are metaphorically brought back from the dead.
되살아난다는 것은 그의 캐릭터들이 은유적으로 죽음에서 다시 돌아온다는 것을 의미합니다.
One of the main characters is metaphorically brought back to life when he sees his daughter after 18 years in the Bastille, or in his words,
주요 캐릭터 중 한 명은 18년 만에 바스티유에서 딸을 보았을 때 은유적으로 다시 삶을 찾게 됩니다. 그의 말에 따르면,
buried alive.
살아 묻히다.
Similarly, Bruce Wayne is metaphorically recalled to life when Catwoman steals his fingerprints,
유사하게, 캣우먼이 브루스 웨인의 지문을 훔칠 때 그는 은유적으로 다시 살아나는 것으로 묘사된다.
forcing him to leave Wayne Manor after eight years of self-imposed isolation.
그를 강제로 웨인 맨션을 떠나게 만들어, 8년간의 자발적인 고립 상태를 끝내게 한다.
I care for no man on Earth, and no man cares for me.
나는 지구上的 누구도 신경 쓰지 않고, 누구도 나를 신경 쓰지 않는다.
Another character named Carton is resurrected when he sacrifices himself for another character,
또 다른 캐릭터인 카르통은 다른 캐릭터를 위해 자신을 희생할 때 부활합니다.
Take my coat. Hurry!
내 코트 가져가세요. 서둘러요!
thus giving meaning to his aimless life.
따라서 그에게 무의미한 삶에 의미를 부여합니다.
This arc is reflected in Catwoman,
이 흐름은 캣우먼에 반영되어 있습니다.
I'll open that tunnel, then I'm gone.
그 터널을 열고 나서는 사라질 거예요.
There's more to you than that.
당신은 그 이상입니다.
who overcomes her selfishness and saves Batman.
그녀는 자신의 이기심을 극복하고 배트맨을 구합니다.
This can also be likened to Officer Foley, who sacrifices his life to save Gotham after being complacent with the takeover.
이것은 Gotham이 점령당하는 것에 안주하던 Officer Foley가 자신의 목숨을 희생하여 Gotham을 구하는 것에 비유될 수 있습니다.
These guys run the city. We've all got to keep our heads down until they can fix this.
이 사람들은 이 도시를 운영하고 있어. 그들이 이 문제를 해결할 때까지 우리 모두 머리를 숙이고 있어야 해.
Carton even quotes the story of Lazarus.
카르틴은 라자로의 이야기를 인용하기도 한다.
Lazarus, of course, being the guy Christ resurrected in the Bible.
물론, 라자루스는 성경에서 그리스도가 부활시킨 사람입니다.
Bruce is metaphorically resurrected when he rebuilds his strength and climbs out of the Lazarus Pit.
브루스는 그의 힘을 다시 회복하고 나사로의 구덩이에서 올라올 때 비유적으로 부활합니다.
Darnay, the guy Carton saved, is given a second chance at life when he is spared from execution.
카튼이 구해준 다르네이는 처형에서 면죄받아 두 번째 인생의 기회를 얻습니다.
And Bruce is again metaphorically resurrected when we find out at the end that he is in fact not dead,
그리고 브루스는 결국 죽지 않았다는 사실이 밝혀질 때 다시 비유적으로 부활합니다.
and is given a second chance to live a more rewarding life.
그리고 더 보람 있는 삶을 살 기회를 두 번째로 얻게 됩니다.
Even the title The Dark Knight Rises invokes a phoenix rising from the ashes.
제목 "다크 나이트 라이즈"조차도 재에서 일어나는 불사조를 연상시킵니다.
The poster for the film swaps out a phoenix for the bat symbol,
영화 포스터는 불사조를 배트 심볼로 교체합니다.
and chapter 23 of A Tale of Two Cities is called Fire Rises.
"두 도시 이야기"의 23장은 "불이 일어나다"라는 제목입니다.
Have we started the fire?
불을 지폈나요?
Yes, the fire rises.
네, 불이 타오릅니다.
Oh yeah, and both texts feature a capitalist named Stryver.
아, 맞아요. 두 텍스트 모두 자본가인 스트라이버가 등장합니다.
You're no mistake, Mr. Stryver.
당신은 실수가 아닙니다, 스트라이버 씨.
At Batman's funeral, Gordon even reads this line about Carton's sacrifice and moral resurrection
배트맨의 장례식에서 고든은 카톤의 희생과 도덕적 부활에 대한 이 대사를 읽는다.
straight from the end of A Tale of Two Cities.
"A Tale of Two Cities"의 마지막 부분에서 직접 인용하겠습니다.
It is a far, far better thing that I do.
내가 하는 일은 훨씬 더 좋은 일이다.
Than I have ever done.
내가 지금까지 한 것보다.
Finally, there's the theme of doubling.
마지막으로, 이중성 주제가 있습니다.
You've probably heard the opening lines,
아마 당신은 첫 번째 대사를 들어본 적이 있을 것입니다.
it was the best of times, it was the worst of times.
좋은 시절이었고, 나쁜 시절이었습니다.
This contrasting between pairs, between best of times and worst of times,
최고의 시기와 최악의 시기 사이의 대조는,
between age of wisdom and foolishness, between epic of belief and incredulity,
지혜와 어리석음 사이, 믿음과 불신의 서사 사이,
happens throughout the whole book.
책 전체에서 발생합니다.
There are two Manets, two cities, London and Paris,
두 개의 마네가 있으며, 두 도시인 런던과 파리가 있습니다.
Darnay has two trials, and Darnay and Carton look the exact same.
다르네는 두 번의 재판이 있고, 다르네와 카르통은 똑같이 생겼다.
In The Dark Knight Rises, there's two cities, Gotham and Bane's Underground,
《다크 나이트 라이즈》에서는 고담과 베인의 지하세계, 두 도시가 등장합니다.
Batman and Bane, two League of Shadows alums who deal with unbearable pain,
배트맨과 베인, 두 명의 그림자 연맹 졸업생은 견딜 수 없는 고통을 다루고 있습니다.
one born in privilege, another born in hell.
특권 속에 태어난 사람과 지옥에서 태어난 사람.
Blake and Batman are both orphans with anger issues,
블레이크와 배트맨은 모두 분노 문제를 가진 고아입니다.
and a constant reminder of the division between body and soul.
몸과 영혼 사이의 분리를 끊임없이 상기시키는 것입니다.
So, what we've got here is probably the most graceful thematic adaptation
그래서 여기 있는 것은 아마 가장 우아한 주제적 각색일 것입니다.
from a classic to a comic book movie in existence.
고전에서 존재하는 만화책 영화로.
But the problem is that on top of developing new themes borrowed from A Tale of Two Cities,
하지만 문제는 '두 도시 이야기'에서 차용한 새로운 주제를 개발하는 것 외에도,
the film also has to juggle the themes established in The Dark Knight.
이 영화는 또한 '다크 나이트'에서 설정된 주제를 잘 다루어야 한다.
And here's where the film starts to stumble.
그리고 여기서 영화가 비틀거리기 시작합니다.
One of the essential themes of The Dark Knight is truth versus lies.
"다크 나이트"의 핵심 주제 중 하나는 진실 대 거짓입니다.
The Dark Knight ends with a noble lie,
다크 나이트는 고귀한 거짓으로 끝납니다.
Batman takes responsibility for the crime he committed,
배트맨은 그가 저지른 범죄에 대해 책임을 집니다.
Batman takes responsibility for Harvey Dent's murders,
배트맨은 하비 덴의 살인에 대한 책임을 진다.
thus denying the fall of Gotham's savior and upholding the image of him
따라서 고담의 구세주가 넘어지는 것을 부정하고 그의 이미지를 지키는 것입니다.
as an ideal symbol of justice and hope.
정의와 희망의 이상적인 상징으로.
Herein lies one of the most squandered opportunities of the film.
여기 영화에서 가장 낭비된 기회 중 하나가 있습니다.
Many incredible works end with a noble lie.
많은 놀라운 작품은 고귀한 거짓말로 끝납니다.
In Joseph Conrad's Heart of Darkness, for example,
요셉 콘래드의 "어둠의 마음"에서, 예를 들어,
Marlowe lies to Kurtz's widow by telling her that Kurtz's last words were her name,
말로는 커츠의 아내에게 커츠의 마지막 말이 그녀의 이름이었다고 거짓말을 한다.
saving her from the truth that he died a deranged psychopath.
그가 정신적으로 불안정한 사이코패스라는 진실에서 그녀를 구하고 있다.
Or in Alan Moore's Watchmen,
혹은 앨런 무어의 왓치맨에서,
the team agrees to preserve Ozymandias' lie that millions were killed by an extraterrestrial force
팀은 수백만 명이 외계의 힘에 의해 죽었다는 오지맨디아스의 거짓을 지키기로 동의합니다.
in order to maintain peace between the US and the USSR.
미국과 소련 간의 평화를 유지하기 위해.
However, both Heart of Darkness and Watchmen end without the truth ever coming out.
그러나 '어둠의 심장'과 '왓치맨' 모두 진실이 결코 드러나지 않고 끝납니다.
We're left to ponder what's more important, the truth or the saving lie?
우리는 진실과 구원하는 거짓 중 무엇이 더 중요한지 고민하게 됩니다.
The Dark Knight leaves us with this same ambiguity,
다크 나이트는 우리에게 같은 모호함을 남깁니다,
but The Dark Knight Rises picks up where these stories left off.
그러나 '다크 나이트 라이즈'는 이 이야기들이 끝난 지점에서 시작됩니다.
Thematically, of course.
주제적으로, 물론입니다.
So finally, we get to see what happens when a noble lie is exposed to the vulgar truth.
결국, 고귀한 거짓이 저속한 진실에 드러날 때 무슨 일이 일어나는지 우리가 보게 되었습니다.
Maybe it's time we all stop trying to outsmart the truth and let it have its day.
아마도 우리 모두가 진실을 지혜로 이기려 하던 것을 그만두고 진실이 그 날을 가질 수 있도록 해야 할 때인 것 같습니다.
Does the film live up to the challenge?
그 영화는 도전에 부응하나요?
Unfortunately, not really.
안타깝게도, 그렇지 않습니다.
At the beginning of The Dark Knight Rises,
어둠의 기사: 라이즈의 시작에서,
we see that the noble lie has manifested itself in the Dent Act,
우리는 고귀한 거짓이 덴트 법안에서 드러나고 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
a piece of legislation that allows cops increased power to prosecute organized crime.
조직 범죄를 기소하기 위해 경찰의 권한을 강화하는 법안.
There are two ways this can be read.
이것은 두 가지 방법으로 읽을 수 있습니다.
One, we can read it as a metaphor for the Patriot Act,
하나는, 이를 애국법에 대한 은유로 읽을 수 있습니다.
a law criticized for giving the government a dangerous amount of power to fight terrorism.
테러와의 전투를 위해 정부에 위험한 수준의 권한을 부여한다는 비판을 받는 법률.
Considering many interpret the Joker's radicalism as a reflection of Al-Qaeda extremism,
많은 사람들이 조커의 급진주의를 알카에다의 극단주의 반영으로 해석하고 있는 점을 고려하면,
this makes sense.
이해가 됩니다.
Or two, Harvey Dent can be read as a Christ figure without resurrection,
또는 두 번째로, 하비 덴트는 부활 없는 그리스도적 인물로 해석될 수 있습니다.
a kind of atheistic interpretation.
일종의 무신론적 해석.
Imagine if Christ never came back to life, but people fabricated the lie that he did
그리스도께서 결코 다시 살아나지 않았다면, 하지만 사람들이 그가 살아났다는 거짓말을 만들어냈다고 상상해보세요.
in order to maintain his divine status and create a religious institution founded on a lie.
신성한 지위를 유지하고 거짓에 기반한 종교 기관을 만들기 위해서입니다.
Based on this reading, Christ, like Dent, would be a false idol,
이 독서를 바탕으로, 그리스도는 덴트처럼 거짓 우상이 될 것입니다.
but one that must be upheld in order to maintain peace and hope.
그러나 평화와 희망을 유지하기 위해 반드시 지켜져야 하는 것입니다.
Fallen idol.
타락한 우상.
Gothamites even celebrate his legacy with Harvey Dent Day,
고담 시민들은 하비 덴트 데이와 함께 그의 유산을 기념하기도 합니다.
which I'm sure will be moved to late December to stimulate the economy.
경제를 자극하기 위해 늦은 12월로 연기될 것이라고 확신합니다.
Harvey Dent Day may not be our oldest public holiday,
하비 덴트 데이는 우리가 가진 가장 오래된 공휴일은 아닐 수 있습니다.
but we're here tonight because it's one of the most important.
하지만 우리는 오늘 밤 여기 있는 이유는 그것이 가장 중요한 것 중 하나이기 때문입니다.
Considered in this light, the Dent Act can be likened to the way that religion has been
이러한 관점에서 볼 때, 덴트 법은 종교가 다루어지는 방식과 유사하게 볼 수 있다.
used to justify overreaching acts of power like the Inquisition.
종교재판과 같은 권력의 과도한 행위를 정당화하는 데 사용되었습니다.
As juicy as this sounds, neither of these extended metaphors actually pan out.
이렇게 듣기 좋은 이야기도 이 두 가지 연장된 은유는 실제로는 성립되지 않습니다.
Because contrary to what the film wants us to assume,
영화가 우리가 가정하기를 원하는 것과는 반대로,
there's no evidence that the product of the lie is corrupt.
거짓의 결과물이 부패하다는 증거는 없다.
In fact, the Dent Act seems to work wonders.
사실, 덴트 법은 놀라운 효과를 발휘하는 것 같습니다.
When you and Dent cleaned up the streets, you cleaned them good.
당신과 덴트가 거리를 청소했을 때, 정말 잘 청소했습니다.
Pretty soon we'll be chasing down overdue library books.
곧 우리는 연체된 도서관 책들을 쫓아다닐 것입니다.
Once Bane reveals the truth that Harvey Dent is a false idol and the Dent Act is built off this lie,
베인이 하비 덴트가 허구의 우상이며 덴트 법이 이 거짓에 기반해 있다는 사실을 밝히자,
it leads to social unrest.
사회 불안을 초래합니다.
So is the film trying to say that bad stuff happens when the truth is revealed?
영화가 진실이 드러날 때 나쁜 일이 발생한다는 것을 말하려고 하는 건가요?
It seems so, considering when Alfred reveals the truth about Rachel choosing Dent over Bruce,
그것이 사실인 것처럼 보입니다. 알프레드가 레이첼이 브루스 대신 덴트를 선택한 진실을 밝힐 때를 고려하면,
it just drives them further apart and encourages Bruce to go on his suicide mission.
그것은 그들을 더욱 멀어지게 하고 브루스가 자신의 자살 임무를 수행하도록 격려합니다.
But the problem comes when the film doubles back to the conclusion of The End of the Dark Knight,
하지만 문제는 영화가 《다크 나이트》의 결론으로 돌아올 때 발생합니다.
because everything is only fixed when the truth is buried and another lie is established.
모든 것이 고정되는 것은 진실이 묻히고 또 다른 거짓말이 세워질 때뿐이다.
He said it to fly out over the water but eject?
그가 물 위로 날아가라고 말했지만 튕겨 나가라고요?
No autopilot.
자동 항법 없음.
At the end, Wayne lies about the Bat's autopilot being broken so that he can fake his death.
결국 웨인은 배트기의 자동 조종 장치가 고장났다고 거짓말을 하여 자신의 죽음을 위장합니다.
Mr. Fox, it's already been fixed.
여보세요, 폭스 씨. 이미 고쳐졌습니다.
Software patch.
소프트웨어 패치.
Six months ago.
6개월 전.
Check the ID on the patch.
패치에 있는 ID를 확인하세요.
Bruce Wayne.
브루스 웨인.
Thus, the narrative of Batman sacrificing himself for Gotham
따라서 배트맨이 고담을 위해 자신을 희생하는 이야기가 전개됩니다.
creates another image of justice for Gotham to revere.
고담이 존경할 또 다른 정의의 이미지를 만들어낸다.
The final lines from A Tale of Two Cities that Gordon quotes during Bruce's funeral
Gordon이 브루스의 장례식에서 인용한 『두 도시 이야기』의 마지막 구절입니다.
reflect Carton's Christ-like sacrifice,
카르튼의 그리스도와 같은 희생을 반영하다,
thereby suggesting that Batman's sacrifice is also Christ-like.
그렇다면 배트맨의 희생이 그리스도를 닮았다는 것을 암시합니다.
However, as the final shots of the movie prove,
그러나 영화의 마지막 장면들이 증명하듯,
Batman did not sacrifice himself for Gotham.
배트맨은 고담을 위해 자신을 희생하지 않았다.
But perhaps it's necessary to believe the lie that he did,
하지만 아마도 그가 그렇게 했다는 거짓을 믿는 것이 필요할지도 모른다.
just as it was necessary to believe the lie that Harvey Dent was noble to the end.
하비 덴트가 끝까지 고결하다는 거짓말을 믿는 것이 필요했던 것처럼.
After spending nearly three fucking hours to find out how this theme of truth will develop,
진실이라는 주제가 어떻게 발전할지 알아내기 위해 거의 세 시간이나 쓰고 나서,
we end up exactly at the same spot as The End of the Dark Knight,
우리는 다크 나이트의 엔드와 정확히 같은 지점에 도착하게 됩니다.
establishing the necessity of a lie to uphold faith in justice.
정의를 믿기 위해 거짓의 필요성을 확립하는 것.
If the theme of the noble lie were to truly develop,
만약 고귀한 거짓의 주제가 진정으로 발전한다면,
we might be presented with a scenario in which the toxic lies lead to so much corruption
우리는 독성 거짓이 너무 많은 부패로 이어지는 시나리오에 직면할 수 있습니다.
that revealing the lie would be more beneficial than letting it fester and destroy Gotham.
그 거짓을 드러내는 것이 고담을 망치고 악화시키는 것보다 더 유익할 것이라는 것을.
The film attempts to do this by suggesting that the corruption of the Dent Act
이 영화는 덴트 법의 부패를 암시함으로써 이를 시도합니다.
leads to Bane's social revolution, as evidenced by Gordon's quote.
고든의 인용에서 증명되는 바와 같이 베인의 사회 혁명으로 이어집니다.
The Batman wasn't needed anymore.
배트맨은 더 이상 필요하지 않았다.
We won.
우리가 이겼어요.
A stone lie.
돌 거짓말.
Nothing is evil.
악은 없다.
Rising from where we tried to bury it.
우리가 그것을 묻으려 했던 곳에서 다시 솟아오르다.
Bane is supposed to be the outcome of this toxic lie.
베인은 이 유독한 거짓말의 결과로 나타나야 한다.
Given Gordon's words, it seems like Bane was meant to function like the Joker did,
고든의 말을 감안할 때, 베인은 조커처럼 기능하도록 설계된 것처럼 보입니다.
as a product of escalation.
상승의 결과로서.
In The Dark Knight, we get super clear exposition that shows the state of society
다크 나이트에서 우리는 사회의 상태를 보여주는 매우 명확한 설명을 받습니다.
that leads to the rise of the Joker.
이는 조커의 출현으로 이어집니다.
Batman has put so many drug dealers out of business and inspired so much fear,
배트맨은 많은 마약 밀매상들을 사업에서 퇴출시켰고, 많은 두려움을 불러일으켰다,
that the mob has been pushed to desperation,
폭도가 절망에 몰렸다는 것,
leading to the rise of a radically antithetical form of Batman's brand of justice, the Joker.
배트맨의 정의와 전혀 다른 형태의 정의인 조커의 부상을 초래하고 있습니다.
It seems Gordon was trying to suggest that when abusive power based on a lie
고든은 거짓에 기반한 남용 권력이 존재할 때를 언급하려고 했던 것 같습니다.
leads to unsavory political and economic tensions, a violent reaction is bound to happen.
이는 바람직하지 않은 정치 및 경제적 긴장을 초래하며, 폭력적인 반응이 일어나는 것은 불가피하다.
But once again, we have no evidence of this corruption at the hands of the Dent Act,
하지만 다시 한 번, 우리는 덴트 법안의 손에 의한 이러한 부패에 대한 증거가 없습니다.
or the lie that justifies it.
그것을 정당화하는 거짓말.
In one scene, Catwoman tricks a man threatening her life by making him use the cell phone of
한 장면에서 캣우먼은 자신의 생명을 위협하는 남자를 속여서 그의 휴대폰을 사용하게 합니다.
a missing congressman, and seconds later, the police bombard in.
실종된 하원 의원과 몇 초 후, 경찰이 들이닥친다.
This can be read as an indication that the Dent Act allows for the monitoring of everyone's
이것은 Dent Act가 모든 사람의 모니터링을 허용한다는 것을 나타내는 것으로 읽힐 수 있습니다.
cell phones, which would make sense given the Patriot Act parallel.
휴대폰은 패트리엇 법과 유사한 점을 고려할 때 이해가 될 것입니다.
But the problem is, this saves Catwoman's life.
하지만 문제는 이것이 캣우먼의 생명을 구한다는 것입니다.
Without this kind of power, Catwoman would be dead.
이런 종류의 힘이 없었다면, 캣우먼은 죽었을 것이다.
Why not show us the negative consequences of invasive surveillance?
침해적인 감시의 부정적인 결과를 우리에게 보여주는 것이 왜 좋지 않을까요?
The film throws away this opportunity to comment on how those in power
이 영화는 권력을 쥔 사람들이 어떻게 행동하는지에 대한 코멘트를 할 수 있는 기회를 포기합니다.
can use a lie to justify excessive authority.
거짓말로 과도한 권위를 정당화할 수 있다.
This brings us to the second theme of the movie.
이것은 영화의 두 번째 주제로 이어집니다.
Pain.
고통.
This theme, like Truth, spends nearly three hours developing,
이 주제는 진실과 마찬가지로 거의 3시간에 걸쳐 발전합니다.
just to bring us back to where we started.
우리가 시작했던 곳으로 되돌아가게 하겠습니다.
At the beginning, Bruce, stricken with physical pain and the pain of losing Rachel,
시작할 때, 브루스는 신체적 고통과 레이첼을 잃은 고통에 시달리고 있습니다.
doesn't leave his mansion.
그는 맨션을 떠나지 않는다.
He overcomes his pain when he heals his back and escapes the Lazarus Pit.
그는 허리를 치료하고 라자루스 피트를 탈출할 때 그의 고통을 이겨냅니다.
But he ultimately gives in to pain again, when he decides to stop being Batman,
하지만 그는 결국 다시 고통에 굴복하게 되는데, 배트맨이 되기를 그만두기로 결정할 때입니다.
fucks off to Italy, and starts living that bored billionaire lifestyle.
이탈리아로 가서 지루한 억만장자 라이프스타일을 살기 시작한다.
Now, I'm going to bring another literary work in here to possibly defend
이제 저는 여기에 또 다른 문학 작품을 가져와서 방어해 볼 것입니다.
the cyclical nature of these two themes.
이 두 주제의 순환적인 특성.
George Orwell's Animal Farm.
조지 오웰의 동물 농장.
See, in Animal Farm, Orwell does a very clever thing.
보세요, '동물농장'에서 오웰은 아주 기발한 일을 합니다.
The term revolution is given a double meaning.
"혁명"이라는 용어는 이중적인 의미를 갖습니다.
On the one hand, it denotes the revolution when the animals overthrow their human oppressors.
한편으로 그것은 동물들이 인간 지배자들을 타도할 때의 혁명을 나타냅니다.
But the original definition of revolution is also given significance
하지만 혁명의 본래 정의도 중요성을 부여받습니다.
because the novel comes full circle.
소설이 완전한 원을 이루기 때문입니다.
It revolves.
그것은 회전한다.
At the end, the pigs are just like the humans they overthrew.
결국, 돼지들은 그들이 전복한 인간들과 다르지 않습니다.
Greedy capitalists.
탐욕스러운 자본가들.
So could the Nolans be playing with this double meaning of the word revolution
그래서 놀란 가족이 '혁명'이라는 단어의 이중 의미를 가지고 놀고 있을 수 있을까요?
by having the themes of pain and truth come full circle in a film about social revolution?
사회 혁명에 관한 영화에서 고통과 진실의 주제가 어떻게 원을 그리는가?
Maybe.
아마도.
Or maybe I'm just giving them too much credit.
아니면 내가 그들에게 너무 많은 기대를 하는 것일지도 몰라.
You guys decide.
여러분이 결정하세요.
The third major theme in the film is social inequality.
영화의 세 번째 주요 주제는 사회 불평등입니다.
But whereas A Tale of Two Cities aptly displays the decadence and corruption
그러나 《두 도시 이야기》는 타락과 부패를 적절하게 보여줍니다.
of the elite that leads to social unrest,
사회적 불안으로 이어지는 엘리트의
The Dark Knight Rises gives us a vague, muddy, and almost nonsensical display
다크 나이트 라이즈는 우리에게 모호하고 흐릿하며 거의 비상식적인 전시를 보여줍니다.
of the social tensions that lead to Bane's false revolution against the rich.
부유한 자들에 대한 베인의 허위 혁명을 초래하는 사회적 긴장감에 대한.
According to Bane, Blackgate Prison is a symbol of the Dent Act's oppression.
베인은 블랙게이트 교도소가 덴트 법의 억압을 상징한다고 말합니다.
Blackgate is overcrowded,
블랙게이트는 과밀 상태입니다.
men and women sometimes share cell blocks,
남성과 여성은 가끔 셀 블록을 공유합니다.
and criminals under the Dent Act don't get parole.
덴트 법에 따라 범죄자는 가석방을 받을 수 없습니다.
Sure, it's harsh and unjust,
물론, 그것은 무섭고 불공정합니다.
but it's hardly the gratuitous cruelty we see in, say, A Tale of Two Cities.
하지만 그것은 예를 들어 '두 도시 이야기'에서 우리가 보는 무분별한 잔인함과는 거의 거리가 멉니다.
These unfortunate realities seem to pale in comparison to the
이러한 불행한 현실들은 ...에 비하면 상대적으로 약해 보이는 것 같습니다.
overwhelming success of the Dent Act.
덴트 법안의 압도적인 성공.
Especially considering that the law's inability to fight crime
특히 법이 범죄와 싸우지 못하는 점을 고려할 때
is a central conflict of the first two films.
첫 두 영화의 중심 갈등입니다.
And even if Blackgate was wrongfully imprisoning people,
그리고 블랙게이트가 사람들을 부당하게 수감하고 있었다 하더라도,
how does that translate to overthrowing the rich?
그것이 부자를 전복하는 것과 어떻게 연결되나요?
Blackgate is a clear stand-in for the Bastille during the French Revolution.
블랙게이트는 프랑스 혁명 동안 바스티유의 분명한 대체물이다.
And drawing that analogy out farther,
그 비유를 더 확장해 보면,
the Dent Act is meant to be the French Le Trait de Cachet,
던트 법은 프랑스의 레 트레 비 카셋(Le Trait de Cachet)을 의미한다.
a kind of warrant issued by the King of France that detained people
프랑스 왕이 발행한 일종의 영장으로, 사람들을 구금하는 데 사용되었습니다.
without being burdened by annoying shit like proof or reasonable suspicion.
증거나 합리적인 의심과 같은 귀찮은 것에 얽매이지 않고.
The Bastille became a symbol for the excesses of the King's authority.
바스티유는 왕권의 과도함의 상징이 되었습니다.
People could be thrown in jail for practicing the wrong religion,
사람들이 잘못된 종교를 실천하다가 감옥에 수감될 수 있습니다.
or criticizing the government, or pissing off the wrong nobleman at the wrong time.
정부를 비판하거나, 잘못된 시기에 잘못된 귀족을 화나게 하는 것.
And when popular rage finally reached a breaking point,
그리고 대중의 분노가 마침내 한계에 이르렀을 때,
the Bastille was an obvious target.
바스티유는 명백한 목표였다.
Problem is, this analogy doesn't really fit,
문제가 되는 것은 이 비유가 실제로는 잘 맞지 않는다는 것입니다.
because Blackgate does none of these things.
블랙게이트는 이 모든 것을 하지 않기 때문입니다.
King Louis didn't go around eradicating the mob
루이 왕은 폭력배를 근절시키기 위해 돌아다니지 않았다.
and making France safe with his authority.
그리고 그의 권위를 통해 프랑스를 안전하게 만들고 있습니다.
And if the Gotham police are abusing their authority, like Louis,
고담 경찰이 루이처럼 권한을 남용하고 있다면,
we're not shown it.
우리는 그것을 보여주지 않았습니다.
I also suppose that this would have complicated the final showdown scene
이것이 마지막 결전 장면을 복잡하게 만들었을 것이라고 생각합니다.
in which the cops are the good guys.
경찰이 좋은 사람인 경우.
So if the Dent Act alone doesn't justify people overthrowing Gotham's social structures,
따라서 덴트 법안만으로 고담의 사회 구조를 전복하는 것이 정당화되지 않다면,
maybe it's something else?
아마 다른 무언가일까요?
The Kid in the Orphanage suggests that the economic situation
고아원 아이는 경제 상황을 시사합니다.
is making orphans go into the sewers and join Bane's army.
고아들이 하수도로 가서 베인의 군대에 합류하게 만드는 것입니다.
There's work down there.
거기 아래에 일이 있어요.
Work?
일?
What kind of work are you going to find in the sewers?
하수도에서 어떤 종류의 일을 찾을 수 있을까요?
More than you can find up here, I guess.
여기서 찾을 수 있는 것보다 더 많은 것 같아요.
But we're given zero indication on how the Dent Act or Blackgate
하지만 우리는 덴트 법이나 블랙게이트에 대한 어떠한 정보도 제공받지 못했습니다.
are disenfranchising the poor.
가난한 사람들을 소외시키고 있다.
The only evidence we see of elite corruption
우리가 엘리트 부패의 증거로 보는 유일한 것
is when Daggett tries to steal Wayne Enterprises from Bruce Wayne.
다겟이 브루스 웨인으로부터 웨인 엔터프라이즈를 훔치려 할 때입니다.
But that's the rich screwing over the rich,
그건 부자가 부자를 속이는 거야,
not the rich screwing over the poor.
부자가 가난한 사람을 착취하는 것이 아니다.
Some people have condemned The Dark Knight Rises
일부 사람들은 '다크 나이트 라이즈'를 비난했습니다.
as anti-Occupy Wall Street propaganda for this very reason.
이와 같은 이유로 반 점령 월가 선전으로 사용됩니다.
It shows a society that seeks vengeance on the rich
부유한 자들에게 복수를 추구하는 사회를 보여줍니다.
for no other reason than they're rich,
그들이 부자라는 이유 외에는 아무런 이유가 없다.
and sets up kangaroo courts to punish them.
그리고 그들을 처벌하기 위해 깡통 재판소를 설정합니다.
No lawyer?
변호사가 없나요?
No witnesses?
증인이 없나요?
What sort of due process is this?
이게 무슨 정당한 절차인가요?
Without actually establishing what these people are rebelling against,
이 사람들이 무엇에 반항하고 있는지 실제로 밝히지 않은 채,
it makes it look like the film is painting Occupy activists
영화가 점령 활동가들을 그리는 것처럼 보이게 만든다.
as nothing more than easily manipulated fascistic clowns.
쉽게 조종당하는 파시즘적인 광대들 외에는 아무것도 아닌.
It's more of an issue of underdeveloped worldbuilding
이는 미개발된 세계관 구축의 문제입니다.
and not necessarily politically charged moralizing.
그리고 반드시 정치적으로 편향된 도덕적 설교는 아닙니다.
As I said earlier, The Dark Knight Rises is far from a bad film.
제가 앞서 말했듯이, 다크 나이트 라이즈는 결코 나쁜 영화가 아닙니다.
It unfortunately falls a bit short,
안타깝게도 다소 부족합니다.
but so goes the tragedy with many trilogies.
그러나 많은 3부작에서 이러한 비극이 발생합니다.
With so many subplots, so many characters, so much ambition,
많은 부 subplot, 많은 캐릭터, 많은 야망이 있는 가운데,
and it being so long,
그리고 그렇게 오래되다 보니,
it's hard not to see why some of this got a little messy.
이런 일이 조금 복잡해진 이유를 모르는 건 쉽지 않다.
None of this even takes into account
이 모든 것은 고려되지도 않습니다.
that this whole social unrest scenario
이 전체 사회 불안 상황
is an elaborate fabrication from the League of Shadows to destroy Gotham.
고담을 파괴하기 위한 그림자의 연합의 정교한 위작입니다.
Which of course begs the question,
물론 여기서 질문이 생깁니다.
why even bother with all this French Revolution stuff?
왜 이렇게 프랑스 혁명에 대해 신경을 써야 할까요?
But that's gonna have to be a subject for another video.
하지만 그건 다른 비디오의 주제가 되어야 할 것 같아요.
With a little more finessing and a tad more attention on worldbuilding,
조금 더 섬세하게 다듬고 세계 구축에 조금 더 주의를 기울이면,
this film could have been a Wisecrackian wet dream,
이 영화는 와이즈크랙의 꿈같은 작품이 될 수 있었어요.
and a fitting conclusion to one of the best trilogies of our time.
우리 시대의 최고의 트릴로지 중 하나에 적합한 결말입니다.
It's almost that, but it's not.
거의 그렇긴 한데, 그렇지는 않다.
Thanks for watching Wisecrack.
Wisecrack을 시청해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Peace.
평화.
But just because this movie is a bit of a mess,
하지만 이 영화가 약간 엉망이라고 해서,
doesn't mean your legal work has to be.
당신의 법률 업무가 그렇게 되어야 한다는 의미는 아닙니다.
See what I did there?
제가 그걸 어떻게 했는지 보셨나요?
LegalZoom is the smart way to take care of your legal needs,
LegalZoom은 귀하의 법적 필요를 처리하는 스마트한 방법입니다.
and they made the process of setting up a new business and more a total breeze.
그들은 새로운 사업을 시작하는 과정을 완전히 수월하게 만들어 주었습니다.
LegalZoom eliminates the guesswork of having to find an attorney you trust,
LegalZoom은 신뢰할 수 있는 변호사를 찾는 데 필요한 추측 작업을 없애줍니다.
wondering how much your legal work will cost,
귀하의 법률 작업 비용이 얼마나 될지 궁금하신가요?
and having to take unnecessary trips to a lawyer's office,
불필요하게 변호사 사무실에 방문해야 하는,
which always has terrible parking anyway.
어차피 주차 공간이 항상 형편없어요.
LegalZoom works with a network of independent attorneys
LegalZoom은 독립 변호사 네트워크와 협력합니다.
to help you with all sorts of projects.
모든 종류의 프로젝트를 도와드리기 위해.
The formation of your company,
회사의 설립,
wills and trusts,
유언과 신탁
trademarks and patents,
상표 및 특허,
contracts,
계약,
and more.
그리고 더 많은 것들.
When we decided to do Wisecrack full-time,
우리가 와이즈크랙을 전업으로 하기로 결정했을 때,
it was really important that we set up our business right.
우리 비즈니스를 올바르게 설정하는 것이 정말 중요했습니다.
Separating our personal stuff from the company
회사의 것과 개인적인 것을 분리하기
and navigating all the intricacies of state and local laws can be a huge pain.
주 및 지방 법률의 복잡함을 탐색하는 것은 큰 골칫거리가 될 수 있습니다.
But LegalZoom offers the services and resources to make sure you get it done right.
하지만 LegalZoom은 당신이 올바르게 일을 처리할 수 있도록 서비스와 자원을 제공합니다.
Whether you need the help with your business,
비즈니스에 도움이 필요하신지 여부,
family planning,
가족 계획,
or general legal advice,
일반 법률 조언을 위해,
LegalZoom is there to help.
LegalZoom은 도움을 드리기 위해 있습니다.
Wisecrack fans get 15% off their purchase,
Wisecrack 팬들은 구매 시 15% 할인을 받습니다.
so head to LegalZoom.com slash Wisecrack to get started,
그러니 LegalZoom.com slash Wisecrack으로 가서 시작하세요.
and save 15% today.
오늘 15% 절약하세요.
Thanks to LegalZoom for sponsoring this video.
이 영상을 후원해주신 LegalZoom에 감사드립니다.
And hey, once again guys, thanks so much for watching.
그리고 다시 한번 여러분, 시청해 주셔서 정말 감사합니다.
We've got lots more planned,
우리는 더 많은 계획이 있습니다.
so make sure to subscribe so you don't miss a thing.
그러니 놓치는 일이 없도록 꼭 구독해 주세요.
I gotta put the finishing touches on our next Westworld video,
나는 다음 웨스트월드 비디오의 마무리를 해야 해.
so catch you later guys.
그럼 나중에 봐요, 여러분.
Peace.
평화.